어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Jipangu State, where the Karakuri people live, is a place of constant conflict.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
무사시 대
코지로이오
Musashi vs.
Kojirō
에도토피아에 평화가 돌아왔다.
Peace has returned to Edotopia.
마을은 다시 활기차졌고,
The village became lively again,
제니가탄의 아내 아카네는 배가 커지고,
Zenigatan's wife Akane's stomach became bigger,
갔다 올게!
See you later!
다녀와.
See you.
아, 청소, 세탁은 돌아와서 내가 할 테니까 쉬고 있어.
I'll do the cleaning and washing; you can take a rest.
알았어.
I know you will.
장도 내가 볼 테니까.
I'll go shopping by myself, too.
그래, 그래!
Yeah, great!
안녕, 아가야!
Hello, my baby!
걱정이 많아.
He's so prone to worrying.
지라이얀은 변함없이 두꺼비 기름을 팔고,
Jiraiyan still sells toad oils,
(록코의 맛있는 물: 브랜드 이름)
(rokko no oishii mizu: delicious water from Rokko; water brand name)
에, 록코의 맛있는 두꺼비 기름 어떠세요?
Would you like delicious toad oil from Rokko?
필요 없어요.
I don't need it.
아, 그래요?
Oh, alright.
오늘도 저녁은 없겠네.
I guess we won't have dinner again today.
우시와카, 벤케이는 에도 성의 무사에게 검술을 가르치며,
Ushiwaka and Benkei teach swordsmanship to the swordsmen of Edo Castle,
목소리를 키워라!
Louder!
예!
Yessir!
이에야스는 그를 찾아온 사이고와 간담을.
Ieyasu has a conversation with Saigo who came to met him,
홋카이도의 바이켄 형제는 밭일에 땀을 흘리고,
Baiken brothers in Hokkaido are sweating for their field works,
그리고...
and...
무사시하고 나머지라 하면 미야코 팔레스에 와 있었다.
Musashi and others are now in Miyako Palace.
무사시, 좀만 더 예의바르게 못 먹겠냐!
Musashi! Can't you eat with manners?
교자이오? 어? 어디이오? 어디? 어디어디어디?
Gyoza-dasu? Where, where? Where? Where, where, where?
센히메 님, 행복해 보여.
Senhime looks happy.
그렇소!
You're right-dasu!
저 둘, 잘 어울려.
Those two look good together.
우리도 잘 어울리오!
We look good together, too-dasu!
저런, 무사시 씨도 참.
Mr. Musashi...
천진한 놈들이야...
They're so simple-minded...
저런.
Oh, no.
맛있소.
Delicious-dasu.
무사시! 내 고기 완자를 잘도!
Musashi! How dare you take my meatball!?
그래도 잘 되었소!
Anyway, isn't it great-dasu?
뭐가!
What is!?
이걸로 센짱이 진정하면 우리도 면직되고 느긋하게 살 수 있소!
If Sen-chan calms down by this, we'll be dismissed and we'll be able to live restfully-dasu!
진정해? 뭔 소리냐.
Calm down? What are you talking about?
결혼 말이오, 결혼. 센짱하고 국왕이 결혼하오.
I'm talking about a marriage-dasu. Sen-chan and the Highness will marry-dasu.
결혼!?
Marry!?
왜 그래, 코지로?
What's wrong, Kojirō?
세, 센히메 님이 결혼?
S- Senhime marries?
저런, 코지로도 참, 아직 국왕 전하께 프로포즈한 게 아니야. 그쵸?
My, Kojirō, I didn't propose to the Highness yet! Right?
네.
Yes.
코지로도 참 설레발친다니까!
Kojirō, you're always jumping to the conclusion too early!
갑자기 가슴이 아파졌다.
My chest started to hurt...
에이이이이이! 멈춰멈춰!
weeeeeeh! Stopstop!
싫어!
Nope!
에이이이이이! 멈춰멈춰!
weeeeeeh! Stopstop!
싫어!
Nope!
멈춰!
Stop!
멈춰멈춰멈춰!
Stopstopstop!
잡았소!
I got you!
자, 다음엔 오츠루가 술래이오!
You're it-dasu, Otsuru!
응!
Yes!
코지로!
Kojirō!
코지로 씨!
Mr. Kojirō!
코지로! 아무리 미용하고 건강에 조심한다고 해도, 아직 자기에는 너무 빠르오!
Kojirō! It's too early to sleep, even if you care about beauty and health-dasu!
아직 해질녁이에요.
It's evening yet.
무사시. 오츠루 씨.
Musashi. Ms. Otsuru.
나는 병에 걸린 것 같다.
It seems that I'm sick.
벼, 병라니, 대체 무슨 병이오?
S- sick? Sick of what-dasu?
모르지만 가슴이 아프구나.
I don't know, but my chest hurts.
가슴이 아파?
Your chest hurts?
예쁜 노을이에요.
What a pretty sunset.
그래.
Yes.
국왕 전하하고 둘이서 이러고 있다니...
To think that I'm with you at a place like this...
센히메, 기뻐!
Senhime's happy!
나도 그래.
Me too.
오, 한 구절 생각났다!
I made a new poem!
저녁 노을로
하늘이 새빨갛게
물들었구나
Evening sunset
dyes the sky over there
in vermilion
와, 지금까지 한 것 중에서 최고에요!
That's the best among the ones you ever did!
센히메도 하나 만들어 봐.
Senhime, you should make one too.
아, 네, 어디...
Oh, okay, well...
됐어요!
I got one!
서쪽 하늘에
저녁 노을 나오면
내일 맑으리
Evening sunset
on the west sky promises
clear tomorrow
이래요.
That's it.
음, 그건 너무 당연하지 않아요?
Don't you think that's too obvious?
하이쿠라는 건, 센히메, 단어 속에 숨겨진 것이 감동시키는 것이에요.
What's important about Haiku is, Senhime, impressing people with a hidden meaning inside words.
더 공부해야겠네요.
You should study more.
네.
Right.
뭐라? 코지로 님이 중한 병에?
What? Mr. Kojirō is sick?
그렇소. 코지로가 저런 걸 보는 건 처음이오.
That's right-dasu. I never saw Kojirō like that-dasu.
제 생각이지만, 이대로라면 코지로 씨, 죽을 지도 몰라요.
It's just my thoughts, but Mr. Kojirō might die at this rate.
언제부터 그 상태가 되었나요?
Since when he's like that?
어디, 센짱 결혼 이야기를 막 했을 때일까...
Let's see... when I said about Senhime's marriage...
결혼?
Marriage?
그렇군요. 그런 것이군요.
I see. I get it.
주베 씨! 뭐가 이상하오! 웃을 일이 아니오!
Mr. Jūbē! What's so funny-dasu? It's not a laughing matter-dasu!
아, 아니, 실례했습니다. 그래도 안심해 주세요. 코지로 님의 병은 목숨을 위협하는 정도의 것은 아닙니다.
Well, no, excuse me. Please be relieved. Mr. Kojirō's sickness isn't something that will put his life at stake.
어?
Huh?
그건 사랑의 병입니다.
It is lovesickness.
사랑의 병?
Lovesickness?
가슴이 아파...
My chest hurts...
천하의 미스터 코지로라는 자가...
How can this happen to me, the unrivaled Mister Kojirō...
코지로!
Kojirō!
어라?
Huh?
무사시냐. 조용히 해 줘라.
Oh, it's you, Musashi. Please be quiet.
뭔 소리이오, 코지로! 나, 알고 있소!
What are you saying-dasu, Kojirō? I know-dasu!
뭐, 뭔 소리냐.
W- what are you talking about?
네 병은 사랑의 병이라는 놈이오!
Your sickness is something called lovesickness-dasu!
사, 사랑의 병?
L- lovesickness?
그렇소! 센짱에게 실례해서 가슴이 아파오는 것이오, 코지로!
Yeah-dasu! Your chest hurts because you did a discourtesy to Sen-chan-dasu, Kojirō!
뭔 이상한 소릴 하고 있냐, 너는.
What are you blabbering about?
지팡구 제일을 노리는 코지로가 실례 정도로 앓아눕다니, 부끄럽소!
It's deplorable to stay in bed because you made a discourtesy, Kojirō, when you're looking to be the number one of Jipang!
나하고의 승부도 안 났으니 죽으면 가만 안 있겠소!
Since we haven't settled this yet, I won't be able to stand this-dasu!
그래, 알겠다, 무사시. 결투다. 누가 강한지 네게 알려 주겠다.
Well, then, Musashi, we'll have a match. I'll show you who's stronger.
그래야 하오.
I knew you would-dasu.
어? 코지로가?
What? Kojirō?
그래요. 그 분, 진지하다 못해 그걸 입으로 이야기를 못 했어요.
Yes. He couldn't tell it by himself, because he's too serious.
코지로가, 나를?
Kojirō... me?
이대로는 코지로 씨가 죽고 말 거에요.
Mr. Kojirō will die at this rate.
코지로 씨를 구할 수 있는 건 센히메 님밖에 없어요!
Only you can rescue Mr. Kojirō, Senhime!
까악까아악
울고 있는 동물은
까마귀일까
The animal that
cries caw caw must be a
crow over there
알겠어. 죽을 정도로 날 사랑해 준다면, 그 애정에 답해줘야만 해!
Alright. If he loves me to the extent he'll die, then I must respond to his devotion!
자, 칼 들어라, 무사시!
Grab your swords, Musashi!
바라던 바오!
I was waiting for this-dasu!
가슴이...
My chest...
코지로, 네 사랑의 병이 낫고 나서 승부를 하오.
Kojirō, we'll have a match after your lovesickness gets cured-dasu.
또 그 소리냐, 무사시. 적당히 넘어갈 생각 마라.
You're still saying that, Musashi? Don't even try to go easy on me.
알겠소. 그렇게까지 말한다면!
Got it-dasu. You said it-dasu!
잠깐!
Stop!
둘 다 그만해!
Stop it, you two!
세, 센히메 님!
S- Senhime!
코지로! 아니, 코지로 씨!
Kojirō! No, Mr. Kojirō!
코지로 씨, 1년 내내 가까이 같이 있으면서, 당신이 저를 사랑해 주고 있다는 걸 알아채지 못했다니, 미안해요.
Mr. Kojirō, I'm really sorry that I didn't realize you loved me, even when we were together for a whole year.
센히메 님...
Senhime...
코지로!
Kojirō!
저, 저기...
E- er...
저, 저기, 무슨 말이신지 저는...
E- excuse me, but I don't understand what's...
어? 가슴 아픈 게 사라졌다.
Huh? My chest doesn't hurt anymore.
뭐야, 물고기 가시가 가슴에 걸려서 아팠구나! 이야, 센히메 님 덕분입니다. 감사합니다.
Oh, it hurted because this fish spine stuck in my chest! Senhime helped me. Thank you.
뭐, 물고기 가시?
What, fish spine?
이야, 잘됐어, 잘됐어, 잘됐어!
This is great! So great! Excellent!
아, 그래! 그거 참 잘 됐네!
Oh, sure! It's really great!
너 따위하곤 살면서 다시는 말 안 할 거야!
I will not talk to you ever again!
대체 뭔 일이야?
What's going on?
뭐라고!? 내가 센히메 님께 실례해서 앓아누워!?
What!? You're saying that I stayed in bed because I was rude to Senhime!?
난 그런 나약한 사내가 아니다! 바보 취급 마라!
I am not a fragile man like that! Don't treat me like an idiot!
무사시! 용서할 수 없다! 결투다!
Musashi! Unforgivable! We'll have a duel!
코지로, 사과하고!
Kojirō, I apologize-dasu!
무사시. 너는 언제부터 그렇게 연약해졌냐.
Musashi. Since when did you become so weak?
어? 연약?
What? Weak?
그렇다.
Yes.
나는 오츠루 씨 험담할 생각은 없다.
I am not insulting Ms. Otsuru.
그러나 오츠루 씨가 나타난 이후로 넌 이상해졌다.
But, ever since Ms. Otsuru appeared, you became strange.
계속 농탕이나 치고, 결혼하오 라고 말이나 하고, 지팡구 제일이 되겠다는 네 목표는 잊었냐!
You're making out and saying "we'll marry-dasu!" all the time. Did you forget about becoming the number one of Jipang?
옛날을 기억해내라. 거칠고 난폭하며 무모했던 때의 무사시를!
Remember the past. Remember the Musashi when he was rough, wild, and reckless!
뒤쫒지 마라!
Do not follow her!
그래, 결투.
Alright. A duel.
받아 주겠소!
I will accept-dasu!
좋다. 내일 아침 6시, 간류 섬이다.
Good. We'll meet at Ganryu Island 6 in morning.
그 자식!
That bastard!
국왕 전하!
Your Highness!
(오구라 백인일수의 23번째 문장)
(23th sentence of Ogura Hyakunin Isshu; translation taken from http://jti.lib.virginia.edu/japanese/hyakunin/index.html)
달 보는 마음
여럿으로 복잡해
서글퍼진다
As I view the moon
Many things come into my mind
And my thoughts are sad
가을이 나를 위해
온 것이 아니리니
Yet it's not for me alone
That the autumn time has come
오, 센히메!
Oh, Senhime!
국왕 전하, 부탁이 있습니다.
Your Highness, I have a favor to ask.
뭔가요?
What is it?
저하고... 저하고 결혼해 주세요!
Please... please marry me!
응, 그것도 괜찮은 생각이네요.
That's a good idea.
그렇게 해요.
Let's do so.
감사합니다!
Thank you so much!
그랬습니까.
I see.
무사시 님과 코지로 님이 결투를.
Mr. Musashi and Mr. Kojirō are having a duel...
다 제 잘못이에요. 그래도, 이대로 둘이 싸운다면 무사시 씨하고 코지로 씨 중 하나는 상처를 입고 말 거에요.
It's all my fault. If they fight each other, one of them will end up being hurt.
그러니까, 부탁드려요, 주베 씨. 그 들을 멈추어 주세요.
That's why I'm asking you a favor, Mr. Jūbē. Please make them stop.
오츠루 씨.
Ms. Otsuru.
네.
Yes?
이건 이해해 주셔야 합니다.
You have to understand them for now.
네?
What?
저희 무예가는 싸우면서 자신을 단련하며 살아 갑니다.
We martial artists fight to improve oneselves.
무사시 님도 코지로 님도 살생을 위해 싸우는 것이 아닙니다.
Both Mr. Musashi and Mr. Kojirō are not fighting to kill.
그것이 무예가의 살아가는 방식입니다.
That is how we martial artists live.
이해해 주십시오.
Please understand.
그런 건 거짓말이야!
That's a lie!
무예가가 살아가는 방식이라 하지만, 주베 씨도 모두도 싸우는 게 좋을 뿐이야!
You're saying that's how martial artists live, but Mr. Jūbē and all others just love fighting!
남자는 다 야만스러워!
All men are barbaric!
싫어! 바보바보바보!
No! You idiot! You idiot! You idiot!
저런.
Oh, well.
여러 가지 생각을 담고 해는 떠올라, 간류 섬에서는 코지로가 지금 이제나저제나 하고 무사시를 기다리고 있었다.
With various thoughts, the sun has risen, and Kojirō is waiting for Musashi eagerly at Ganryu Island.
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
늦어! 무사시 놈, 대체 뭘 하고 있는 거야!?
He's late! What the hell is Musashi doing!?
누군가하고 뭔가 약속했던 것 같은 기분이...
I think I promised something with somebody...
그렇소! 코지로하고 결투가 있소!
Right-dasu! I have a duel with Kojirō-dasu!
으악! 지각이오!
Wah! I'm late-dasu!
무사시 놈, 겁에 질려서 달아난 게 틀림없어. 흥! 애초에 그게 다인 남자 놈이였냐. 다시 봤다!
That Musashi bastard must have run away because he's so frightened! Hmph!
He was a man of that kind at the first place! I underlooked him!
아, 아니, 다시, 잘못 봤다!
Er, no, correction; I overlooked him!
사무라이 씨! 간류 섬엔 왜 가시나?
Mr. Samurai! Why are you going to Ganryu Island?
결투이오!
To have a duel-dasu!
칼도 없이?
Without a sword?
으악! 잊고 왔소!
Wah! I forgot-dasu!
뭘 하고 있냐, 무사시! 완전히 지각이다!
What are you doing, Musashi!? You're completely late!
미안하오!
I'm sorry-dasu!
해 보자, 무사시!
Let's do this, Musashi!
좋소!
Right-dasu!
무사시, 그 칼은 뭔 장난이냐?
Musashi, are you trying to be funny with that sword?
흥이오! 코지로를 상대로 천공환을 쓰는 건 아깝소!
Hmph-dasu! My Tenkūmaru is too valuable to use it to you, Kojirō-dasu!
억지도 그게 최후다!
That will be your last futile retort!
간류! 츠바메가에시!
Ganryu! Tsubamegaeshi!
끝장이다!
I'll finish you!
끈질긴 놈...
How stubborn...
어, 어라, 센짱!
H- hey, Sen-chan!
뭐라고!?
What!?
거짓말이오!
It was a lie-dasu!
무사시! 넌 왜 그렇게 심술궂냐?
Musashi! Why are you so deliberately malicious?
거짓말도 소변이오.
A lie is also a pee-dasu!
그 소리를 지껄일 거라면 거짓말도 방편이다!
(shōben: urine, hōben: means)
If you're gonna say that, then it's "a lie is also a means!"
비슷한 것이오!
They are similar-dasu!
정말, 아무것도 생각 안 하는 놈이군!
Really, you're one guy that never thinks!
조금은 생각하오!
I do think for a bit-dasu!
뭘 생각하고 있는지 말해 봐라!
Tell me what you're thinking about!
예를 들어, 아침밥이라던가...
For example, morning meals...
그리고!
And?
점심밥이라던가...
Lunch...
그리고!
And?
저녁밥이라던가...
Dinner...
네 머리에는 먹을 것밖에 없냐!
Do you ever think about something that isn't about food!?
오츠루도 생각하오.
I think about Otsuru too-dasu!
오츠루, 지금쯤 뭘 하고 있을까...
I wonder what's Otsuru doing by now-dasu...
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
아, 오츠루 생각하니, 나, 왠지 들리는 것 같소.
Now that I'm thinking about Otsuru, it's like I'm hearing her-dasu!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨! 칼 가지고 왔어!
Mr. Musashi! I brought your swords!
오츠루!
Otsuru!
무사시 씨, 어제는 미안했어.
Mr. Musashi, I apologize about what happened yesterday.
괜찮소. 이건 오츠루가 잘못한 게 아니오. 코지로가 나빴소.
It's alright-dasu. It's not Otsuru's fault-dasu. Blame Kojirō-dasu.
나, 무사시 씨 방해되지 않도록 할 테니까 힘껏 싸워.
I won't bother you, Mr. Musashi, so, please fight all you can.
알겠소. 오츠루도 괴롭힌 코지로를 엉망으로 만들어 주겠소!
Got it-dasu. I'll wreck Kojirō, for harassing you, Otsuru-dasu!
지껄임도 거기까지다. 해 보자, 무사시.
Your blabbering ends now. Let's finish this, Musashi.
좋소!
Sure-dasu!
잠깐만.
Just a moment.
항복이냐?
Giving up?
오줌 타임이오.
Pee time-dasu.
오츠루, 잠깐 저기 보시오!
Otsuru, look the other side for a moment-dasu!
응.
Alright.
쳇, 이 틈에 나도 해 둘까.
Tch. Maybe I'll do that too.
둘 다, 이제 그만했으면 좋겠는데.
I want those two to stop by now...
가자, 무사시!
Let's do this, Musashi!
좋소!
Right-dasu!
나, 자라면 무사시 씨 아내가 될 거야!
I'll become your wife when I grow up, Mr. Musashi!
그러니까, 강한 사무라이가 되어 줘!
That's why you have to become a strong samurai!
알겠소! 나, 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되겠소!
Got it-dasu! I'll become the number one martial artist of Jipang-dasu!
무사시 씨...
Mr. Musashi...
무사시! 코지로!
Musashi! Kojirō!
-다들!
-다들! 무슨 일이오!
-Everyone!
-Everyone! What's up-dasu?
주베 씨한테 결투 이야기 듣고 서둘러 왔어.
We heard about your duel from Mr. Jūbē, so we hurried our way to here.
그렇소!
I see-dasu!
아직 결판은 안 난 모양이군요.
It seems that the match isn't over yet.
그래, 안 늦어서 다행이다!
Yeah, it's great that we weren't late!
우리가 입회할 테니까 신경쓰지 말고 싸워 주셔!
We'll be witnesses, so please fight, and don't mind us!
고맙소. 코지로 따위는 곧장 해치워 주겠소!
Thank you-dasu. I'll finish up Kojirō right away-dasu!
그건 내가 할 말이다!
That's my line!
뭐야, 다들 멈추게 하려 온 게 아니네.
Oh, they aren't here to stop them.
실망이야.
How disappointing.
가자, 무사시!
Let's do this, Musashi!
언제라도 환영이오!
Come whenever you're ready-dasu!
비검 츠바메가에시!
Secret Sword Tsubamegaeshi!
다 보이오!
I can see you-dasu!
뭣이!?
What!?
코지로하고 계속 싸워 왔던 덕분인지 다음 동작이 보이오!
I can see your next move, probably because I kept fighting with you all along-dasu!
흥, 무사시, 성장했구나.
Hmph. Musashi, you grew up.
처음 만났을 때는 그냥 얘새끼였더니, 지금은 내게 다가온 듯 하구나.
You were nothing more than a brat when we first met, but it seems that you came closer to me by now.
흥이오! 내 쪽이 코지로보다 성장했소!
Hmph-dasu! I grew up more than you, Kojirō-dasu!
어딜 봐서!
And how is that!?
내게는 사랑이 있소!
I have love-dasu!
사랑!?
Love!?
내게는 지팡구 제일이 되어서 오츠루하고 결혼하겠다는 사랑의 목표가 있소!
I have the objective of love, of marrying Otsuru after becoming the number one of Jipang-dasu!
코지로! 네게는 목표 있소?
Kojirō! Do you have an objective-dasu?
저런, 무사시 씨도 참, 부끄럽게.
My, Mr. Musashi, you're embarrassing me!
내 목표?
My objective?
센히메?
Senhime?
네, 네!
Y- yes?
뭘 생각하고 있었어?
What were you thinking?
아, 아니, 그게...
W- well, that's...
나는 알아.
I know.
예?
What?
새는 좋겠지.
I envy those birds.
자유롭게 하늘을 날 수 있지.
They can fly freely.
분명 하늘의 저편에서 찾는 무언가가 있겠지.
They must be finding for something, at the other of the sky.
센히메도 새같아.
Senhime, you're like a bird.
예?
Yes?
아까부터 넓은 하늘을 날고 싶다고, 날개가 근질근질하고 있겠지.
Your wings must be itching to fly on the wide open sky, from a while ago.
날개는 제게는 없어요.
I don't have wings.
나는 나무야. 대지에 단단히 뿌리내린 나무야.
I am a tree. A tree that rooted deeply to the ground.
날아갈 수 없어.
I cannot fly.
센히메. 넓은 하늘을 날아.
Senhime. You should fly on the wide open sky.
무언가를 찾다가도, 힘들면 돌아와서 내 가지에서 날개를 쉬어.
Find whatever you wanted, and when you're tired, come back to me, and rest on my branch.
국왕 전하...
Your Highnes...
죄송합니다!
I'm sorry!
뭘 하신 것입니까.
What did you do?
실례했다.
I was rude.
예?
Hm?
비, 빈틈이다...
C- chink in the armor...
뭡니까?
What's this?
큰일이야, 다들! 에도토피가 다수의 닌자에게 공격당하고 있어!
We have a problem, everyone! Edotopia is being attacked by a large number of ninjas!
저, 정말입니까? 그건 큰일이네요!
A- are you serious!? That's a big problem!
한조는 아직 죽지 않았던 거야. 한조가 에도토피아를 공격하고 있어!
Hanzō wasn't dead yet. Hanzō is attacking Edotopia!
-뭣이오!?
-한조가!?
-What-dasu?
-Hanzō!?
다들 초공전에 타! 에도토피아에 가자!
Everyone, get onto Chokuden! Let's go to Edotopia!
아직 살아 있었다니, 한조도 참 끈질긴 놈이구나!
To know that Hanzō's still alive, he's really persistent!
예, 그건 거짓말입니다.
Oh, that's a lie.
무사시 님과 코지로 님의 결투를 멈추기 위해 센히메 님이 생각해 내신 거짓말입니다.
Senhime made up this lie to stop Mr. Musashi and Mr. Kojirō from fighting.
거짓말이야?
A lie, eh?
철렁했네...
You surprised us...
무사시, 승부는 나중이다.
Musashi, we'll finish this later.
그렇소.
Right-dasu.
나도 무언가 목표를 세우도록 하지.
I'll make an objective of my own.
그건 잘 됐소. 그 때 다시 승부이오.
That's great-dasu. We'll have a match again after that-dasu.
OK.
하늘을 난다는 건 기분 좋네.
Flying feels good!
네. 마치 새가 된 것 같아요.
Yes. It's just like as if we became birds.
호적수를 넘어 우정으로 맺어진 무사시와 코지로. 사내의 꽃길은 미래로 이어진다.
More than rivals, Musashi and Kojirō are tied together with friendship. Their flowery road will continued to the future.
그러나, 마지막에 이기는 것은 사랑일 지도 모른다.
But, it might be the love, what wins at last.
영원한 사랑의 날을 잡을 때까지, 꺾이지 말고 나아가라! 그것이 무사시의 길, 무사시 로드이다.
Until you catch the day of love, do not be discouraged advance! That is the road of Musashi: Musashi Road.
싸우고 맞았어
I fought and I got beaten
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
I can't lose, so take my blow!
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
다음 시간 즐거운
Next is delightful lunchtime
급식일 텐데
But it's not delightful today
선생님의 벼락이
The thunder of my teacher
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
only hit me and nobody else
사정을 말해도
I tried to explain
들어주지 않는 채
But he won't listen
어떻게 해도 역시
Now whatever I do
눈물이 나오고 말아
I end up crying
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
왠지 안타까워
you'll feel downhearted